Guide to the Karen Stamm Papers TAM.212
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Karen Stamm Papers
1970-2004
1970-1990
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Stamm, Karen
Carroll, Tamar
TAM.212
11.25 Linear Feet in 11 record cartons and 1 half-size manuscript box.
Karen Stamm participated in several women's reproductive rights campaigns and organizations during the 1970s and 1980s. This collection consists of correspondence, reports, background papers, and publications related to her efforts with those organizations for reproductive rights and against sterilization abuse, particularly of low-income women and women of color.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions with the exception of student papers not written by Karen Stamm. These materials are closed in compliance with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA).
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Karen Stamm to Tamiment Library in 1999. An oral history interview of Stamm conducted by Tamar Carroll was donated in 2004. The accession numbers associated with these gifts are 1999.018 and 2014.108.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in three series: Series I: Personal and academic papers, arranged by topic; Series II: Organizations, arranged alphabetically; and Series III: Subject files, arranged alphabetically. Some materials were arranged and re-foldered before 2017.
Historical/Biographical Note
Karen Stamm participated in several women's reproductive rights campaigns and organizations during the 1970s and 1980s, including the National Women's Health Network (NWHN), the Reproductive Rights National Network (R2N2), the Committee to End Sterilization Abuse (CESA), and its successor, the Committee for Abortion Rights and Against Sterilization Abuse (CARASA). She received her law degree from Rutgers Law School in 1985 and practiced landlord and tenant law and estate planning.
Through NWHN, R2N2, CESA, CARASA, and other organizations, Stamm advocated for reproductive rights and affordable healthcare for all women, regardless of race or socioeconomic status. She worked to end sterilization abuse as population control and for greater transparency of sterilization practices among hospitals and municipal healthcare agencies.
Scope and Contents
The Karen Stamm Papers (1970-2004, bulk: 1970-1990) document Stamm's dedication to and participation in several women's reproductive health and rights organizations at national and state levels during the 1970s and 1980s. The collection also touches on tensions between advocates for abortion rights and those against sterilization abuse.
Included are correspondence, reports, pamphlets and other publications from these organizations. Also included are newspaper clippings and photocopies of clippings and articles that Stamm collected on abortion, sterilization abuse, AIDS, women's health, and related legislation.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Born-digital materials have not been transferred and may not be available to researchers. Researchers may request access copies. To request that material be transferred, or if you are unsure if material has been transferred, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Reproductive rights -- United States; Feminism -- United States.; Women -- Health and hygiene -- United States.; Feminists -- United States.; Sterilization (Birth control) |z United States.; Abortion -- United States.; Committee to End Sterilization Abuse (New York, N.Y.); Committee for Abortion Rights and Against Sterilization Abuse (New York, N.Y.); Stamm, Karen; Carroll, Tamar
- Series I: Personal and academic papers, 1970-2004; 1.25 Linear Feet in one record carton and one half-size manuscript box. 700 megabytes on one compact disc.
  Scope and Contents
  Series I contains correspondence, some of Stamm's law school records and papers, and an oral history interview with Stamm conducted by Tamar Carroll.
  Arrangement
  Materials have been arranged by topic in loose chronological order.
  - Correspondence and papers, 1977-1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1979-1990 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Sarah Wernick, sterilization, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Tom Shapiro, chapter draft, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Betsy Hartmann, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Notes and papers, 1980-1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Personal papers, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Law school, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Law school, background papers, 1979-1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Conference on Women and the Law, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Law school, 1980-1984 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Rutgers Law School, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Family Law papers re Lee Ann Grady, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Law school notes, 1982, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Law school notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Law school papers, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Law school, 1984, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Law school, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Law school: civil rights, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Psychiatry and the Law seminar, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Law school: notes, readings, syllabi, 1973-1985 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Law school: readings, briefs (photocopies), 1865-1984 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Sterilization: legal briefs, 1970-1983 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Draft: "What are the risks of sterilization?", undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - CD-R: Karen Stamm interview by Tamar Carroll, 2004 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Student papers not by Karen Stamm - CLOSED, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    Conditions Governing Access
    CLOSED in compliance with FERPA regulations.
  - Student papers not by Karen Stamm - CLOSED, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Series II: Organizations, 1970-1998; 5.5 Linear Feet in 5.5 record cartons.
  Series II contains organizational notes, minutes, correspondence, reports, background briefs, flyers, questionnaires, and publications from Stamm's participation in national women's reproductive rights groups. Organizations represented include Planned Parenthood, the National Women's Health Network (NWHN), Reproductive Rights National Network (R2N2), and the Committee to End Sterilization Abuse (CESA), which evolved into the Committee for Abortion Rights and Against Sterilization Abuse (CARASA).
  Materials are arranged in the order in which they were received, alphabetically by organization name and in loose chronological order within each organization. Publications are loosely arranged at the end of the series.
  - American Civil Liberties Union: Hyde Amendment, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - ACLU: Reproductive Freedom Project, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Committee to End Sterilization Abuse (CESA): Statement of purpose, bylaws, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - CESA: Minutes, membership meetings, notes, outlines, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - CESA, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - CESA, 1975-1979 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - CESA, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - CESA: internal documents, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - CESA: minutes, meetings, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - CESA: payments, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - CESA: prison inmate correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - CESA: international project, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - CESA: minutes, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - CESA/ Committee for Abortion Rights and Against Sterilization Abuse (CARASA): NY state lobbying efforts, 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - CESA: GAC Intro 1105, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - CESA, 1977, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - CESA: minutes, meetings, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - CESA: report, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - CESA, 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - CESA: correspondence re Planned Parenthood, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - CESA: questionnaire correspondence, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - CESA: NYC hospitals sterilization survey, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - CESA: background publications, 1970-1978 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - CESA: notes, drafts, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - CESA: Karen Stamm notes on Right to Life, other topics, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - CESA/ CARASA, 1976-1979 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - CARASA: NYC sterilization issues, 1977-1980 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - CARASA, 1978-1983 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - CARASA, 1978-1982 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - CARASA, 1978-1984 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - CARASA: internal documents, 1979-1981 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - CARASA: lobbying, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - CARASA: notes, 1980, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - CARASA, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - CARASA: News & Extras, 1980-1983 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - CARASA: News & Extras, 1980-1986 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - CARASA: Family Protection Act clippings, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - CARASA: Ms. article, "Taking the Offensive", 1981 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - CARASA: Dollars & Sense article, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - CARASA: homophobia, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - CARASA: NYC HHC Sterilization Advisory Committee, 1981-1984 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - CARASA: NYC HHC Sterilization Advisory Committee, 1981-1984 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - CARASA, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - CARASA: case study of socialist feminist organizing, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - CARASA: flyers, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Campaign to Keep Abortion Fair, Safe and Funded in NYS, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Center for Constitutional Rights Docket Report, 1978-1982 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Coalition for the Reproductive Rights of Workers, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - CONTROL, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Coalition for the Medical Rights of Women, 1976-1980 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Coalition for the Medical Rights of Women, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Coalition for the Medical Rights of Women, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Coalition for the Medical Rights of Women, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Committee to Defend Reproductive Rights, 1980-1982 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Consumer Health Information and Resource Center, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - International Women's Day, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Mobilize for Women's Lives, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - National Abortion Rights Action League: legal abortion speaker's notebook, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - National Center for Health Statistics, 1976-1985 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - National Center for Health Statistics: Vital Statistics Report, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - National Center on Women and Family Law, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - National Organization for Women, 1973-1998 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - National Right to Life Convention, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - National Women's Health Network (NWHN), 1978-1980 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - NWHN: background materials, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - NWHN: Harris Co. Hospital District, 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - NWHN: meetings, agendas, 1980-1986 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - NWHN: Senate testimony, 1980-1982 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - NWHN: organizational records, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - NWHN: Depo Provera Project, 1980-1983 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - NWHN: Sterilization Committee, 1980-1984 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - NWHN paper: Sterilization Abuse, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - NWHN: Sterilization abuse report, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - NWHN, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - NWHN: Sterilization Abuse Committee, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - NWHN: Reproductive Rights Committee, 1981-1983 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - NWHN: executive director's report, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - NWHN: legislation, Hatch amendment, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - NWHN, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - NWHN: hospital sterilization questionnaires, I, 1981-1983 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - NWHN: hospital sterilization questionnaires, II, 1983, undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - NWHN: hospital sterilization questionnaires, III, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - NWHN: hospital sterilization questionnaires, IV, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - NWHN: hospital sterilization questionnaires, V, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - NWHN: hospital sterilization questionnaires, VI, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - NWHN: hospital sterilization questionnaires, VII, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - NWHN Network News, 1978-1983 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - NWHN Network News, 1982-1990 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - NWHN Network News, 1984-1990 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - NWHN Reproductive Rights Committee, 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - NWHN Reproductive Rights Committee, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - NWHN abortion rights organizing kit, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - NWHN Boston Conference on Women and Health, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - New York City Health and Hospitals Corporation (NYC HHC), 1975-1979 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - NYC HHC guidelines, 1975-1979 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - NYC sterilization survey of hospitals, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - NYC HHC: sterilization regulations, annual report, 1978-1990 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - NYC HHC, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - NYC HHC, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - NYC HHC: sterilization guidelines, 1982-1992 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - NYC HHC: Hysterectomy Consent Committee, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - NYC HHC: statistics, 1982-1988 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - NYC women's newsletters, 1980-1981 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - NYS legislation affecting women, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - NYS sterilization legislation, 1978-1985 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - NYS sterilization legislation, 1979-1985 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - NYS sterilization legislation, 1986-1989 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - NYS Task Force on Young Women, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Planned Parenthood: Papers and policy statement, 1969-1976 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Planned Parenthood: Brochures and pamphlets, 1968-1979 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Planned Parenthood: Brochures and pamphlets, 1973-1977 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Planned Parenthood: General, 1975-1980 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Planned Parenthood: International student program seminars, 1976-1978 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Planned Parenthood: General, 1976-1990 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Planned Parenthood: Feminist Women's Health Center letters, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Planned Parenthood: General, 1977-1979 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Planned Parenthood: World Population Washington Memo newsletters, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Planned Parenthood: Fact-finding forums, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Planned Parenthood: Justice Fund, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Planned Parenthood: NYS Legislature voting records, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Planned Parenthood: Human Problem of Abortion: Medical and Legal Dimensions, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Planned Parenthood: Family planning legislative conference trip, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Planned Parenthood: Alan Guttmacher Institute, 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Planned Parenthood: Litigation updates, 1991-1994 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Reproductive Rights National Network (R2N2), 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - R2N2, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - R2N2 newsletter, 1981-1983 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - R2N2: slideshow on sterilization, population control, imperialism, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - R2N2 HEW 1979 sterilization regulations, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - R2N2, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Sterilization & Informed Rights Consent Project, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Women's National Abortion Action Coalition, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - YMCA/NGO National working seminar on Population Development, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Health Right Women's Health Forum newsletter, 1974-1979 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Newsletters, general, 1972-1981 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Newsletters, general, 1974-1986 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Leaflets, brochures, 1970-1982 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Boston Women's Health Book Collective (BWHBC), 1979 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - BWHBC packet 24, 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - BWHBC packet 25, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - BWHBC packet 26, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - BWHBC, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - BWHBC, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Family Planning Perspectives, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - George Washington University Population Reports, 1972-1977 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - George Washington University Population Reports, 1974-1980 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - George Washington University Population Reports, 1973-1977 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - George Washington University Population Reports, 1975-1977 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Health Pac, 1975-1980 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Notes from the Third Year, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Triple Jeopardy, Third World Women's Alliance, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Reproductive rights publications, 1975-1981 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Population publications, 1976-1977 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Women's health publications, 1973-1979 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Publications, miscellaneous, 1944-1976 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - CESA Demonstration Banner (Box Shared Tamiment 023)
- Series III: Subject files, 1970-1990; 4.5 Linear Feet in 4.5 record cartons.
  Series III consists of clippings, photocopies, articles, and background papers Stamm collected on subjects pertaining to reproductive rights and women's health.
  Subject files are arranged in the order in which they were received, alphabetically by subject. Clippings are minimally arranged chronologically. Some files were arranged before 2017.
  - Abortion, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Abortion reprints, 1970-1979 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Abortion, 1979-1981 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Abortion, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Abortion, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Abortion, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Abortion counseling, 1988-1990 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Abortion Con Con, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Abortion demographics, 1982-1989 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Abortion: informed consent, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Abortion funding, 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Abortion clinic harrassment, 1988-1990 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Abortion: international, 1989-1990 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Abortion: medical, 1979-1982 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Abortion: parental notice, 1988-1990 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Anti war movement, 1971-1981 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Bibliographies, 1976-1979 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Bibliographies, 1977-1979 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Bronx Coalition Against Sterilization Abuse, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Cancer, 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Carcinogens and birth defects, 1980-1981 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Church-state, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Contraception, 1977-1982 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Contraception, 1983-1990 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Demographics, 1984-1988 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Depo Provera, 1980-1983 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Depo Provera, 1982, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Depo Provera, 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Equal Rights Amendment, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Eugenics, 1966-1979 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Eugenics laws, 1975-1979 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Eugenics, 1975-1980 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Eugenics, 1975-1982 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Eugenics, 1982-1983 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Eugenics: Ruby v Massey, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Eugenics laws, legal documents, 1978-1988 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Eugenics bibliography, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Environmental health, OCC, 1979-1990 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Fetal experimentation, 1987-1990 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Healthcare, NYC, 1977-1979 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Healthcare, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - India: public health, 1976-1978 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Infertility, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Invasive surgery, 1981-1988 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - In vitro fertilization, 1988-1989 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Knowledge Control: Issue of Abortion, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Lasch, C. Haven in a Heartless World (photocopy), 1977 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Lesbian healthcare, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Native American women, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - NJ Public TV, 1976-1977 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - OSHA, 1977-1981 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Population control, 1975-1990 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Pregnancy: surveillance, 1988-1990 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Psychiatric hospitals: policies, 1975, undated (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Rape and sterilization: legal briefs, documents, 1940-1970 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - RU 486, 1988-1990 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Science at the Crossroads, 1931 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Sexual assault: legal representation, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Sterilization abuse, 1974-1981 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Sterilization abuse, global, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Sterilization demographics, 1976-1982 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Sterilization: Forced sterilization testimonies, 1973-1975 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Sterilization: global, 1977-1978 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Sterilization: hospital policies, 1975-1978 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Sterilization: medical, 1977-1978 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Sterilization and mental retardation, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Sterilization: Puerto Rico, 1974-1978 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Sterilization regrets, 1980, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Sterilization regulations, 1974-1977 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Sterilization: UK, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Surrogate motherhood, 1988-1989 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Tallahassee Feminist Women's Health Center, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Women workers, 1962, undated (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Clippings, photocopies, 1972-1990 (Box 10, Folder 1-25)
  - Voluntary Sterilization and Informed Consent, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - HEW: state implementation of sterilization regulations, 1979-1980 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - HEW: state implementation of sterilization regulations, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Clippings re sterilization, 1975-1982 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Clippings re sterilization, 1971-1982 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Campaign to remove Antonio Silva from Lincoln Hospital, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - HEW 1979 sterilization regulations: National Women's Law Center, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - HEW 1979 sterilization regulations: Federal registers, 1981-1982 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - HEW 1979 sterilization regulations: National Women's Health Network, 1979-1982 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Health Policy Advisory Center bulletins on women's health, 1970-1977 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Clippings: sterilization data and demographics, 1974-1983 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Douglas v Holloman: CCR and NYC HHC, 1975-1977 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Douglas v Holloman: court documents, 1975-1977 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Clippings: surgical sterilization risks, 1972-1982 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Clippings: surgical sterilization risks, 1972-1982 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Clippings: eugenics laws, 1968-1979 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Clippings: sterilization costs and medicaid coverage, 1974-1976 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Public Citizen Health Research Group: Sterilization abuse reports, 1975-1981 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Clippings: Eugenics, 1975-1982 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Clippings: Eugenics, poverty, racism, birth control, 1972-1979 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - California Medical Association v Lackner, 1978-1979 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Clippings: Medical and legal issues of sterilization, 1972-1980 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Clippings: Attitudes toward sterilization, 1971-1981 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Clippings: US and world population control, 1970-1980 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Public Citizen's Health Research Group: surgical sterilization, 1973-1978 (Box 11, Folder 25)